A Guide to the Helen Norris Cummings Papers, 1865-1949
Alexandria Library, Local History/Special Collections
- Subject Files: World Revolution - Subject Indexes [Incomplete] (Box 72N)
  - Subject Files-World Revolution (Box-folder 72N:1)
  - Subject Files-World Revolution (Box-folder 72N:2)
  - Subject Files-YMCA (Box-folder 72N:3)
  - Subject Files-Youth (Box-folder 72N:4)
  - Subject Files-Youth (Box-folder 72N:5)
  - Subject Files-Youth Movement (Box-folder 72N:6)
  - Subject Files-Youth Movement (Box-folder 72N:7)
  - Subject Files-Young Pioneers (Box-folder 72N:8)
  - Subject Files-Young Pioneers (Box-folder 72N:9)
  - Subject Files-Misc. Communism/Socialism (Box-folder 72N:10)
  - Subject Files-Misc. Communism/Socialism (Box-folder 72N:11)
  - Subject Files-Misc. Religion (Box-folder 72N:12)
  - Subject Files-Misc. Women (Box-folder 72N:13)
  - Subject Files-Misc. (Box-folder 72N:14)
  - Subject Files-Subject Indexes [Incomplete] (Box-folder 72N:15)
- Subject Files-George Washington Bicentennial 1932 (Box 72O)
- Personal/Family (Box 72P)
  - Personal/Family-Norris Cummings, 1849-1875 (Box-folder 72P:1)
  - Personal/Family-Norris Cummings, 1877-1889 (Box-folder 72p:2)
  - Personal/Family-Norris Cummings, 1890-1903 (Box-folder 72P:3)
  - Personal/Family-Norris Barratt, 1889-1915 (Box-folder 72P:4)
  - Personal/Family-Genealogical Materials (Box-folder 72P:5)
  - Personal/Family-Genealogical Materials (Box-folder 72P:6)
  - Personal/Family-Genealogical Materials (Box-folder 72P:7)
  - Personal/Family-Genealogical Materials (Box-folder 72P:8)
  - Personal/Family-Deaths, Marriages, 1851-1930 (Box-folder 72P:9)
  - Personal/Family-Misc. financial, 1869-1930 (Box-folder 72P:10)
  - Personal/Family-Misc. memorabilia (Box-folder 72P:11)
  - Personal/Family-Misc. memorabilia (Box-folder 72P:12)
  - Personal/Family-Helen N. Cummings's own notes and writings (Box-folder 72P:13)
  - Personal/Family-Helen N. Cummings's own notes and writings (Box-folder 72P:14)
  - Personal/Family-Helen N. Cummings's drawings and captions (Box-folder 72P:14a)
  - Personal/Family-Death/Estate of Helen N. Cummings 1949-1975 (Box-folder 72P:15)
  - Personal/Family-Diary-Clipping Book 1888-1906 (Box-folder 72P:16)
  - Personal/Family-Helen N. Cummings Financial Records 1920s-1949 (Box-folder 72P:17)
  - Personal/Family-misc. (Box-folder 72P:18)
- Oversize (Box 72Q)
- Bound volumes 1850-1929 (Box 72R)
- Bound volumes-Bible 1773 (Box 72S)
- Bound volumes-Bible 1858 (Box 72T)
- Bound volumes-Bible 1837 (Box 72U)
- Unidentified photo plates (Box 72V)
  - Unidentified photo plates (Box-folder 72V:1)
  - Unidentified photo plates (Box-folder 72V:2)
- Unidentified photo plates (Box-folder 72W)
  - Unidentified photo plates (Box-folder 72W:1)
  - Unidentified photo plates (Box-folder 72W:2)
  - Unidentified photo plates (Box-folder 72W:3)